Thomas Szasz Papers
Thomas Szasz Papers
- Correspondence-subject files
  - Hutchings Society, 1969; 1980,; undated (Box 31)
  - H, miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 31)
  - Ibañez, Richard A., 1964 (Box 32)
  - Ichheiser, Gustav, 1966; 1969 (Box 32)
  - Illinois Society for Mental Health, 1949-1950; 1953 (Box 32)
  - Illinois, State of (various), 1953-1955; 1958,; 1966 (Box 32)
  - Independent Institute, 1989; 1995-1997,; 2001 (Box 32)
  - Independent Review, 1996; editor Robert Higgs; includes manuscript submission by Szasz (Box 32)
  - Indiana University, 1965; 1969-1970; includes law school, press, etc. (Box 32)
  - Indiana University Northwest, 1974 (Box 32)
  - Inquiry, 1977-1983; undated (Box 32)
  - Institute for Humane Studies, 1969-1974; 1977,; 1992-1994,; undated (Box 32)
  - Institute of Psychiatry, 1975-1978 (Box 32)
  - Institute for Psychoanalysis, 1952; 1955-1957,; 1960-1962 (Box 32)
  - Institute of Society, Ethics, and the Life Sciences, 1975-1976; 1980 (Box 32)
  - Institute for the Study of Contemporary Social Problems, 1983 (Box 32)
  - Institute for the Study of Drug Addiction, 1964-1965; 1971-1972 (Box 32)
  - Institute for the Study of Sport and Society, 1970-1971 (Box 32)
  - Institutum atque Academia, 1972-1974 (Box 32)
  - Intellectual Digest, 1971-1973 (Box 32)
  - Intercollegiate Review, 1967; 1970-1971 (Box 32)
  - Internal Revenue Service (IRS), 1955-1957; 1962,; 1972,; 1990 (Box 32)
  - International Academy of Forensic Psychology, 1969-1972 (Box 32)
  - International Center for Integrative Studies, 1973 (Box 32)
  - International Commission for Human Rights, 1972-1974 (Box 32)
  - International Congress of Psychotherapy, 9th, Oslo, 1972-1973 (Box 32)
  - International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1963-1964; 1966-1967,; undated (Box 32)
  - International Forum on Antiprohibition of Drugs, 1988; includes full text of papers; 2 folders (Box 32)
  - International Journal of the Addictions, 1966; 1971 (Box 32)
  - International Journal Press, 1972 (Box 32)
  - International Journal of Psychiatry, 1967 (Box 32)
  - International Journal of Psycho-Analysis, 1961-1963 (Box 32)
  - International Journal of Psychoanalytic Psychotherapy, 1978 (Box 32)
  - International Psychoanalytic Association, 1984; membership directory of national, regional, state, and local chapters (Box 33)
  - International Science Press, 1966-1967 (Box 33)
  - International Social Science Journal, 1972-1973 (Box 33)
  - International Symposium on Circumcision (Box 33)
  - International Symposium on Pain / Symposium international sur la douleur, 1966-1967; includes Cahn, Charpentier, Devereux (Box 33)
  - International Symposium on Schizophrenia, John J. Madden Center, Walter Fisher, Robert deVito (Box 33)
  - International Universities Press, 1956; 1968 (Box 33)
  - ISKCON (International Society for Krishna Consciousness), 1983 (Box 33)
  - Island Consultation Center, 1977 (Box 33)
  - "Italy", 1979 (Box 33)
  - Ithaca College, 1974 (Box 33)
  - I, miscellaneous (Box 33)
  - J. S. Canner & Company, 1961-1966; 1969 (Box 33)
  - "J'Accuse!", 1979; article by Szasz about Dan White; includes drafts and proofs of article, responses from readers, criticism, etc. (Box 33)
  - Jaccard, Rolland, 1977-1979 (Box 33)
  - Jackson, Don, 1957-1964; undated (Box 33)
  - Jaggard, R. S., 1972; 1975 (Box 33)
  - Jamestown Community College, 1976 (Box 33)
  - Janus Society of America, 1966 (Box 33)
  - Jarrett, Beverly, 1976-1979 (Box 33)
  - Jefferson Community College, 1975-1976 (Box 33)
  - Jeffery, C. R., 1963 (Box 33)
  - Jelliffe, Belinda, 1966; 1970,; undated (Box 33)
  - John Wiley & Sons, 1973; 1980-1999,; undated; 4 folders (Box 33)
  - Johns Hopkins University Press, 1985 (Box 33)
  - Johnson, Adelaide, 1954; 1957 (Box 34)
  - Jones, Ernest, 1952; 1956-1957 (Box 34)
  - Jones, Henry E., 1970; 1972 (Box 34)
  - Joseph, (Sir) Keith, 1971 (Box 34)
  - Joslyn, Marc L., 1995-1996 (Box 34)
  - Jourard, Sidney M., 1957; 1960 (Box 34)
  - Journal of the Albert Einstein Medical Center, 1969 (Box 34)
  - Journal of the American Medical Association (JAMA), 1967-1969; 1997 (Box 34)
  - Journal of Clinical Epidemiology, 1995 (Box 34)
  - Journal of Forensic Psychology, 1969 (Box 34)
  - Journal of the History of the Behavioral Sciences, 1965 (Box 34)
  - Journal of Humanistic Psychology, 1971-1974; 1978,; 1980,; 1983-1984,; 1987-1998,; 2001 (Box 34)
  - Journal of Law and Human Behavior, 1975; 1981 (Box 34)
  - Journal of Medical Ethics, 1994; 2000-2002 (Box 34)
  - Journal of Medicine and Philosophy, 1995; 1997 (Box 34)
  - Journal of Mind and Behavior, 1979-1980; 1984,; 1990,; 1994 (Box 34)
  - Journal of Nervous and Mental Disease, 1957-1973; 2 folders (Box 34)
  - Journal of Psychedelic Drugs, 1972 (Box 34)
  - Journal of Public Law, 1971 (Box 34)
  - Journal of Women's Health, 1998 (Box 34)
  - Judicial Conference of the District of Columbia Circuit, 1964-1965 (Box 34)
  - J, miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 34)
  - Kansas State University, 1976 (Box 34)
  - Kaplan, Eugene, 1978; 1990,; 1992 (Box 34)
  - Karpf, Ronald J., 1987 (Box 34)
  - Kassai-Farkas, Akos, 1993-1995 (Box 34)
  - Kavka, Selig J., 1953-1963 (Box 34)
  - Kazan, Elia, 1965-1969; 1972 (Box 34)
  - Keddie, Ken, 1992 (Box 35)
  - Keene, J. Calvin, 1966-1968 (Box 35)
  - Keller, Hans, 1975-1981; 1984; mostly personal, on BBC letterhead; 2 folders (Box 35)
  - Kennedy, Robert F., 1967 (Box 35)
  - Kephart, Robert D., 1976; 1998 (Box 35)
  - Kesey, Ken, 1962 (Box 35)
  - Kessler, Elizabeth, 1955; 1958,; 1977,; 1986 (Box 35)
  - Keuka College, 1964-1967 (Box 35)
  - Kiado (publisher), undated (Box 35)
  - King, Larry, 1976; 1988 (Box 35)
  - Klaebe, Ken, 1970-1972 (Box 35)
  - Klein, Daniel, 1992-1993; undated (Box 35)
  - Knapp, Peter H., 1957 (Box 35)
  - Knappman, Elizabeth Frost, 1981; 1983,; undated (Box 35)
  - Kniffin, Hazen G., 1960-1965; 1970 (Box 35)
  - Knight, James A., 1961 (Box 35)
  - Knopfelmacher, Frank, 1977; 1982 (Box 35)
  - Kohl, Chuck, 1978-1979 (Box 35)
  - Kohut, Heinz, 1955-1957 (Box 35)
  - Kokomo Tribune, 1971 (Box 35)
  - Kolb, Lawrence C., 1958; 1979 (Box 35)
  - Kommission für Verstösse der Psychiatrie gegen Menschenrechte [Commission for Psychiatric Violations of Human Rights], 1980 (Box 35)
  - Korda, Geza, 1962-1963 (Box 35)
  - Korda, Michael, 1980 (Box 35)
  - Kovacs, Ernest, 1964-1966 (Box 35)
  - Kramer, Maria K., 1959-1960 (Box 35)
  - Kraus, Arthur James (Foundation for Intellectual Freedom and Peace, Inc.), 1979 (Box 35)
  - Kristal, Leonard, 1981 (Box 35)
  - Kroiss, Gerhard M., 1994-1995; undated (Box 35)
  - Kruger, Arthur N., 1966 (Box 35)
  - Kubie, Lawrence S., 1956-1960; 1965-1966,; 1970 (Box 35)
  - Kuhn, Basil J., 1975-1976; 1986,; 1990 (Box 35)
  - Kun, Miklos, 1978-1980 (Box 35)
  - "Kup's Show" (WMAQ TV), 1970 (Box 35)
  - Kurtz, Paul, 1978 (Box 35)
    See also The Humanist; Free Inquiry; Prometheus Books.
  - KYW (Cleveland, OH, radio station), 1965 (Box 35)
  - K, miscellaneous (Ka-Ke), 2 folders (Box 35)
  - K, miscellaneous (Kh-Ku) (Box 36)
  - Lafayette Clinic, 1956 (Box 36)
  - Laing, Ronald D., 1966; 1990,; 1994; includes letters from wife Marguerita and son Adrian (Box 36)
  - Laissez Faire Books, 1972; 1987-1992,; 1996,; undated (Box 36)
    See also Rich, Andrea Millen.
  - Laissez Faire Books, 1990; "messages from your friends and admirers around the world" (Box 36)
    See also Thomas S. Szasz Award and Center for Independent Thought.
  - The Lancet, 1972-1973; 1978,; 1985,; 1990,; 1994-1998,; 2002-2003 (Box 36)
  - The Lancet, 1988; responses to article by Anatoly Koryagin (Box 36)
  - Langer, Susanne, 1959 (Box 36)
  - Langley Porter Neuropsychiatric Institute, 1956-1958; 1962-1965 (Box 36)
  - Lantos, Barbara, 1955 (Box 36)
  - Laor, Nathaniel, 1982-1987 (Box 36)
  - LaPlante, Joseph A., 1963-1966 (Box 36)
  - Larkin, Mary, 1963-1966; 1970,; 1976,; 1979,; undated (Box 36)
  - Law and Society Review, 1968 (Box 36)
  - Law, Liberty, and Psychiatry
    - Pre-publication comments, 1963 (Box 36)
    - Reader responses, 1963-1966 (Box 36)
  - Lawler, Denis James, 1995; regarding the case of Jamin Potamkin (Box 36)
  - Learning Publications Inc., 1985-2003; undated; 2 folders (Box 36)
  - Leary, Timothy, 1960-1962 (Box 37)
  - Lebensohn, Zigmond, 1956-1960; 1963-1965 (Box 37)
  - Lebowitz, Lotti and Marshall, 1960-1961; 1980,; 1985 (Box 37)
  - Legal Aid Society of Milwaukee, 1979; 1982 (Box 37)
  - Lehmann, Lydia, 1979-1981; 1990,; undated (Box 37)
  - Lehrman, Nathaniel S., 1960-1963; 1966,; 1979 (Box 37)
  - Leifer, Ronald, 1963-1965; 1968-1969,; 1978,; 1981,; 1985-1986,; 1990 (Box 37)
  - Leighton, Alexander H., 1957; 1970 (Box 37)
  - Leiter, Manning K., 1957; undated (Box 37)
  - Lemniscaat Publishers, 1972; J.L. Boele Van Hensbroek (Box 37)
  - Leon, Seymour, 1971 (Box 37)
  - Leonard, Frank, 1966; 1971 (Box 37)
  - Levatter, Ross, 1982-1983; 1994-1995 (Box 37)
  - Levine, David L., 1957-1958 (Box 37)
  - Levine, Maurice, 1952-1960; 1964 (Box 37)
  - Levinson, Joseph E., 1970; 1992-1993 (Box 37)
  - Levinson, Steven H., 1993 (Box 37)
  - Levy, David A., 1992-1997 (Box 37)
  - Levy, William, 1958-1959; 1963 (Box 37)
  - Lewis, Florence M., 1970-1972 (Box 37)
  - Lewis, Harvey Allen, 1955; 1960-1961 (Box 37)
  - Lewis, Janet, 1987; includes several copies of her paper, "An idea and its consequences: The Szaszian critique of psychiatry"; 2 folders (Box 37)
  - Lewis, William C., 1960-1962 (Box 37)
  - Liberation, 1962-1964; 1969 (Box 37)
  - Libertarian Alliance, 1981; 1993-1994 (Box 37)
  - Libertarian Party, 1973; 1976-1979,; 1988,; 2000; includes New York, California, Colorado as well as Canada (Box 37)
  - Libertarian Review, 1972-1974; 1977-1981,; undated (Box 37)
  - Libertarians for Life, 1978-1979 (Box 37)
  - Liberty, 1988-1990; 1994 (Box 37)
  - Library of Congress, 1991 (Box 37)
    See also Copyright registrations.
  - Lichtenstein, Heinz, 1961; 1964 (Box 37)
  - Lieberman, E. James, 1960-1961; 1996 (Box 37)
  - LIFE, 1965 (Box 37)
  - Lifton, Robert J., 1963 (Box 37)
  - Lilly, John C., 1966 (Box 37)
  - Lindsey, Duncan, 1978 (Box 37)
  - Linsie, John B., 1963 (Box 37)
  - Lipton, Samuel D., 1965-1970; 1976-1984,; undated; 3 folders (Box 38)
  - Little, Brown and Company, 1968; 1991 (Box 38)
  - Lockwood, Timothy D., 1966-1967 (Box 38)
  - Loewald, Hans W., 1955-1958 (Box 38)
  - Loewenstein, Rudolph M., 1960-1962 (Box 38)
  - Lohmann, Hans, 1970-1971; regarding translations of Swedish review of MMI (Box 38)
  - London Review of Books, 1982 (Box 38)
  - Lorand, Sandor, 1953; 1957-1958 (Box 38)
  - Loria, Donald W., 1952-1953; 1959-1962,; 1967; includes wife Fayette (Box 38)
  - Los Angeles Times, 1973; 2001 (Box 38)
  - Lotspeich, William D./Sylvia, 1959; 1965 (Box 38)
  - Louis, Joe, 1970 (Box 38)
  - Louisiana State University Press, 1975-1976; 4 folders (Box 38)
  - Louisiana State University Press, 1977-1978; 1989; 3 folders (Box 39)
  - Lowenstein, Francoise Pallavicini, 1963; 1969,; undated (Box 39)
  - Loyola College (Montreal), 1970 (Box 39)
  - Loyola University (New Orleans), 1977 (Box 39)
  - Lukacs, John, 1970; 1982,; 1985 (Box 39)
  - Ludwig von Mises Institute, 1990-1992; 1997 (Box 39)
  - Luft, Eric v.d., 2001; curator, SUNY Upstate Historical Collections; includes draft of piece on Szasz for his review (Box 39)
  - Lynch, Alberto Benegas, See ESEADE.
  - L, miscellaneous, 4 folders (Box 39)
  - MacAllister, Carol, 1979-1983; undated (Box 39)
  - Macalpine, Ida, 1954; 1957,; 1970 (Box 39)
  - Macfarlane, Patricia, 1957-1959; undated (Box 39)
  - Machan, Tibor, 1973; 1977-1978 (Box 39)
  - Macmillan Company, 1960-1964 (Box 39)
  - Macmillan Company, 1965-1973; 1978-1982,; 1988,; 1996; 2 folders (Box 40)
  - Magyar Radio, 1994 (Box 40)
    See also Zeley, Laszlo.
  - Mahrer, Alvin R., 1962; 1965 (Box 40)
  - Maine Conference on Human Services, 1974 (Box 40)
  - Malefyt, Mary H., 1964-1966 (Box 40)
  - Manaker, Esther, 1964-1965 (Box 40)
  - Mannoni, Octave, 1976 (Box 40)
  - Marchi, M.L., 1969 (Box 40)
  - Marcuse, Herbert, 1965-1966 (Box 40)
  - Marcy State Hospital, 1956-1959; 1962 (Box 40)
  - Margolis, Gerald J., 1964-1966 (Box 40)
  - Margolis, Joseph, 1964-1965 (Box 40)
  - Mariner, Allen S., 1971 (Box 40)
  - Marks, Ann, 1953-1960 (Box 40)
  - Marmor, Judd, 1954; 1959-1960,; 1964-1965 (Box 40)
  - Marshall, Myron H., 1968-1969 (Box 40)
  - Marshall, Wade H., 1969-1970 (Box 40)
  - Martin Secker & Warburg Ltd., 1971 (Box 40)
  - Mary Imogene Bassett Hospital, 1970; 1975-1976 (Box 40)
  - Maryland Psychiatric Research Center, 1970-1971 (Box 40)
  - Maslow, Abraham, 1961; 1966 (Box 40)
  - Mason, Percy, 1956-1958 (Box 40)
  - Mass, Larry, 1979-1982 (Box 40)
  - Massachusetts General Hospital, 1958; 1963,; 1976 (Box 40)
  - Massachusetts Mental Health Center, 1959; 1962-1965,; 1971 (Box 40)
  - Masserman, Jules, 1953; 1959,; 1980 (Box 40)
  - Mattachine Society Inc. of New York, 1965; 1968-1970 (Box 40)
  - Maxwell, Richard, 1964-1965 (Box 40)
  - May, Robert M., 1980; 1987 (Box 40)
  - May, Rollo, 1960; 1979; features a significant amount of correspondence with Robert Epstein about a Festschrift for Rollo May (Box 40)
  - Mayo Clinic, 1969; 1994 (Box 40)
  - McCall, Raymond, 1963 (Box 40)
  - McElroy, Wendy, 1993-1994 (Box 40)
  - McGill University, 1958; 1968-1970; includes Dept of Psychiatry, "McGill Reporter" student newspaper (Box 40)
  - McGurren, William J., 1966-1967 (Box 40)
  - McIntosh and Otis, Inc., 1960-1983; 1986-2002; Szasz's agents; 9 folders (Box 41)
  - McLaughlin, Janet S., 1980-1982 (Box 42)
  - McWilliams, Carey, 1964 (Box 42)
  - Meacham, Andrew, 1996 (Box 42)
  - Medical Economics, 1956; 1959-1961,; 1969 (Box 42)
  - Medical Opinion & Review, 1967-1971; general (Box 42)
  - Medical Opinion & Review, 1967-1968; reader responses (Box 42)
  - Medical Press, Inc., 1955-1956 (Box 42)
  - Medical Protective Company, 1955-1956 (Box 42)
  - Medical World News, 1961; 1966,; 1970-1971,; 1977 (Box 42)
  - Meehl, Paul E., 1956; 1960 (Box 42)
  - Meerloo, Joost A. M., 1960-1963; 1965,; undated (Box 42)
  - Meier, Kathryn, 1964 (Box 42)
  - Meiers, Joseph, 1963-1964 (Box 42)
  - Men of Achievement, 1973 (Box 42)
  - Mendell, David, 1953 (Box 42)
  - Menninger Foundation, 1953-1958; 1989 (Box 42)
  - Menninger, Karl, 1952-1958; 1962,; 1967,; 1971,; 1988-1989,; undated (Box 42)
  - Menninger, William C., 1959 (Box 42)
  - Mental Health Association in Forsyth County (North Carolina), 1977 (Box 42)
  - Mental Health Social Workers Conference (Minnesota), 1969 (Box 42)
  - Mental Hygiene, 1972 (Box 42)
  - Mental Patients' Association, 1971 (Box 42)
  - Mental Research Institute, 1964-1965 (Box 42)
  - Mesa Vista Hospital, 1969 (Box 42)
  - Metamedicine, 1980-1983; 2 folders (Box 42)
    See also Theoretical Medicine.
  - Metropolitan Life Insurance Company, 1960; 1967 (Box 42)
  - Michael Reese Hospital, 1954-1955 (Box 42)
  - Michigan Group for Psychoanalytic Study, 1958 (Box 43)
  - Michigan Psychological Association, 1968; 7th Annual Conference (Box 43)
  - Michtom, Alice, 1968; 1976-1980,; 1984,; 1990,; 1993 (Box 43)
  - Midway Counseling Center, 1973-1974 (Box 43)
  - Miller, Mark, 1971-1973; undated; includes manuscript by Miller and Jerome Curry, "Hypocritic Oath"; 2 folders (Box 43)
  - Miller, Milton H., 1961-1963; 1970 (Box 43)
  - Millett, Kate, 1990 (Box 43)
  - Milton Friedman Prize for the Advancement of Liberty, 2001 (Box 43)
  - Milton H. Erickson Foundation, 1986-1990; 1995-1996,; 2000,; 2003 (Box 43)
  - Minnesota Association of Human Service Technologies (MAHST), 1973-1974 (Box 43)
  - Minnesota Social Service Association, 1973-1974 (Box 43)
  - Minnick v. California Department of Corrections, 1976-1977; law firm Carroll, Burdick, and McDonough; clippings (Box 43)
  - Minogue, Kenneth, 1966-1967; 1992 (Box 43)
  - Mira Costa High School (California), 1980 (Box 43)
  - Mirikitani, John M., 1992 (Box 43)
  - Mirsky, Harold S., 1964-1965 (Box 43)
  - Mirsky, I. Arthur, 1956-1958 (Box 43)
  - Mitchell, Chet, 1985; 1989-1990 (Box 43)
  - Mix, Eloise, 1980 (Box 43)
  - Moellenhoff, Fritz, 1955-1957 (Box 43)
  - Mohawk Valley Community College, 1973-1974 (Box 43)
  - Molina, Fernando, 1965-1966; 1969 (Box 43)
  - Molnar, Hans, 1987-1988; 1997-1998 (Box 43)
  - Mondadori (publisher), 1971-1974; 1985,; undated; 2 folders (Box 43)
  - Montana Medical Education Research Foundation, 1976 (Box 43)
  - Moore, Hamilton D. (attorney), 1993-1994 (Box 43)
  - Morgan, John P., 1969; 1990-1992 (Box 43)
  - Morgan, Robert, 1971 (Box 43)
  - Morris, Edward, 1962; 1965 (Box 43)
  - Morris, Robert, 1962-1965 (Box 43)
  - Motive Magazine, 1962; 1966 (Box 44)
  - Mowrer, O. Hobart, 1959; 1962 (Box 44)
  - Mudd, Samuel A., 1975-1980; undated (Box 44)
  - Murphy, Debbie, 1978-1981 (Box 44)
  - Murphy, Timothy, 1979-1983 (Box 44)
  - "Myth of Mental Illness" responses
    - Publisher responses, 1958-1959; 1963 (Box 44)
    - Reader responses, 1960-1963; undated; 3 folders (Box 44)
  - M, miscellaneous (Ma-Mon), 5 folders (Box 44)
  - M, miscellaneous (Moo-My) (Box 45)
  - Nagy, Judy, 1978-1980; 1991,; 1996 (Box 45)
  - Nagy, Peter, 1977-1982; 2001 (Box 45)
  - NAPRIJKD (publisher), 1979 (Box 45)
  - National Association for Mental Health, 1961; 1969 (Box 45)
  - National Catholic Reporter, 1972 (Box 45)
  - National Commission on Marihuana and Drug Abuse, 1971 (Box 45)
  - National Council on Crime and Delinquency, 1972-1973 (Box 45)
    See also Rubin, Sol.
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH), 1977; grant application, "The right to suicide" (Box 45)
  - National Features Syndicate, 1971 (Box 45)
  - National Forum, 1979; 1992 (Box 45)
  - National Institute of Education, 1971 (Box 45)
  - National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH), 1953-1957; 1960-1972,; 1978,; undated; includes grant application, "The right to suicide"; 2 folders (Box 45)
    See also United States Public Health Service (USPHS).
  - National Legal Program on Health Problems of the Poor, 1970 (Box 46)
  - National Medical Audiovisual Center, 1969-1970 (Box 46)
  - National Organization of Circumcision Information Resource Centers (NOCIRC), 1994 (Box 46)
  - National Review, 1961-1967; 1970-1976,; 1985,; 1989-1996,; undated; includes material on NR taking formal position on drug law reform; 2 folders (Box 46)
    See also Buckley, William F. Jr.
  - National Science Foundation (NSF), 1970; 1975-1977 (Box 46)
  - National Society for Medical Research, 1959 (Box 46)
  - National Tattler, 1971 (Box 46)
  - Nature, 1994 (Box 46)
  - NBC Television, 1960-1961; 1966,; 1972,; 1975-1976 (Box 46)
  - Neil, Sandra E., 1991 (Box 46)
  - Nemiroff, Robert A., 1961-1964 (Box 46)
  - Nesbit, Louis, 1965 (Box 46)
  - Network Against Psychiatric Assault (NAPA), 1974 (Box 46)
  - Neville, Laura W., 1993-1995; 1998 (Box 46)
  - New Challenges of Humanistic Psychology, 1998 (Box 46)
  - New England Journal of Medicine, 1956; 1959-1961,; 1964-1972,; 1975-1978,; 1984,; 1997 (Box 46)
  - New Europe College, 2006 (Box 46)
  - New Individualist Review, 1970 (Box 46)
  - New Mexico Institute of Mining and Technology, 1969-1970 (Box 46)
  - New Mexico State University, 1980-1981 (Box 46)
  - New Physician, 1961; 1968-1969 (Box 46)
  - New Republic, 1964-1968; 1976-1977,; 1982,; 1989; includes some reader responses to his article, "The ethics of psychoanalysis" (Box 46)
  - New Review, 1973; 1976-1977,; undated (Box 46)
  - New School for Social Research, 1967; 1972 (Box 46)
  - New Scientist, 1971 (Box 46)
  - New Society, 1971 (Box 46)
  - New York Academy of Sciences, 1958-1959; 1965 (Box 46)
  - New York Society of Clinical Psychologists, 1965-1966 (Box 46)
  - New York State Bar Association, 1961 (Box 46)
  - New York State Psychiatric Institute, 1961-1963; 1983 (Box 46)
  - New York Times, 1957-1981; 1987,; 1991,; 1995-1996,; undated (Box 46)
  - New York Times, 1966; reader responses to Szasz's article "Mental Illness is a Myth" (Box 46)
  - New York Times Book Review, 1961; 1964-1971,; 1975,; 1979 (Box 46)
  - New York University, 1960; 1964,; 1976,; 1979; 2 folders (Box 46)
  - Newman, Francine H., 1978-1979 (Box 47)
  - Newsday, 1970; 1976,; 1978,; undated (Box 47)
  - Newsday, 1993; Sol Wachtler article (Box 47)
  - Newsweek, 1965; 1973,; 1991 (Box 47)
  - Noble, Douglas, 1957; undated (Box 47)
  - Noll, John O., 1978; 1981-1983 (Box 47)
  - Norden, Heinz, 1971 (Box 47)
  - North American Newspaper Alliance, 1963; 1966; includes draft of article on Kennedy mental health bill (Box 47)
  - North American Society of Adlerian Psychology, 1989 (Box 47)
  - Northwestern University, 1964; 1967-1969 (Box 47)
  - NSP (publisher), 1995; 2002 (Box 47)
  - N, miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 47)
  - Oaklawn Center, 1966; 1977; 3 folders (Box 47)
  - Oasis Center for Human Potential, 1975-1977 (Box 47)
  - Ochsner, Alton, 1974 (Box 47)
  - O'Connell, Walter, 1962-1965 (Box 47)
  - Oden, Thomas C., 1980 (Box 47)
  - Ohio Northern University, 1975-1976; conference, "Conflicting rights in health care" (Box 47)
  - Ohio State University Program for the Study of Crime and Delinquency, 1977 (Box 47)
  - Ohio State Law Journal, 1972; 1977 (Box 47)
  - Oklahoma State Psychological Association, 1966 (Box 47)
  - Oliver, Jeff, 2003 (Box 47)
  - Omni (magazine), 1979-1980; 1987-1988 (Box 47)
  - Onondaga County Medical Society, 1958-1961 (Box 47)
  - Ontario Educational Communications Authority, 1974; 1976 (Box 47)
  - Ontario Ministry of Health, 1976 (Box 47)
  - Open Court Publishing Company, 1989; 1993 (Box 47)
  - "The Open Mind" (TV show on WNBC), 1966 (Box 47)
  - Orgel, Sidney A., 1962; 1980,; 1983-1984 (Box 47)
  - Orso, Leo, 1971-1972 (Box 47)
  - Osheroff, Raphael, 1982; undated (Box 47)
  - Otto, Owen, 1969 (Box 48)
  - Overseas Publishing Associates (UK) Ltd., 1995 (Box 48)
  - Oxford University Press, 1969; 1975,; 1978-1982,; 1985,; 1991,; undated (Box 48)
  - O, miscellaneous (Box 48)
  - Pacific Law Journal, 1992 (Box 48)
  - Pacific News Service, 1978 (Box 48)
  - Pain, 1972-1974; 1978-1979,; 1988 (Box 48)
  - Paladin Books (division of Granada Publishing), 1971-1973 (Box 48)
  - Palos, Marta, 1991 (Box 48)
  - Pantheon Books, 1965; 1970,; 1974-1976 (Box 48)
  - Parade, 1963; 1974 (Box 48)
  - Parents Interested in Education (PIE), 1977 (Box 48)
  - Parents' Magazine, 1977-1978 (Box 48)
  - Parke, C. J., 1980 (Box 48)
  - Parlour, Richard R., 1963 (Box 48)
  - Parsons, Anne, 1963-1964 (Box 48)
  - Parsons, Talcott, 1959 (Box 48)
  - Patient letters, A-S, letters from individuals requesting help or advice; 3 folders (Box 48)
  - Patient letters, T-Y and unsigned, letters from individuals requesting help or advice (Box 49)
  - Paul B. Hoeber, Inc., 1956-1963 (Box 49)
    See also Hoeber, Paul and Betty and Harper and Row, Inc.
  - Paul, Julius, 1964-1965; 1969-1970 (Box 49)
  - Pearl, Norman H., 1969-1972; 1975-1978,; 1981,; undated (Box 49)
  - Pediatrics, 1969; 1976,; 1994 (Box 49)
  - Pedro, Luis, 1977-1980 (Box 49)
  - Penguin Books, 1974; 1981,; 1988-1989 (Box 49)
  - Pennsylvania League for Nursing, 1973; 1976-1977 (Box 49)
  - Pennsylvania State University, 1977; 1986 (Box 49)
  - Penthouse (Switzerland), 1980 (Box 49)
  - Pergamon Press, 1978-1981 (Box 49)
  - Permissions to quote others, requests from Szasz to quote others in various of his books
    - for The Age of Madness, 3 folders (Box 49)
    - for In the Name of Help, based on the authors included, possibly an early title for "The Age of Madness" (Box 49)
    - for Karl Kraus and the Soul Doctors, most is with publishers Frederick Ungar and Jan Van Loewen Ltd. (Box 49)
    - for A Lexicon of Lunacy, 1992 (Box 49)
    - for Liberation By Oppression (Box 50)
    - for The Manufacture of Madness, 3 folders (Box 50)
    - for The Mental Health Ethic (Box 50)
    - for Psychiatric Justice, includes release forms from patients/families (Box 50)
    - for miscellaneous pieces (Box 50)